19 Garden Heights Avenue Glenview, Hamilton 3206

【 (+64) 022-461-3787 | ☑ jj@josejibin.com | ♠ josejibin.com | ☑ josejibin | jibin-jose

Summary_

A self-motivated developer with 5+ years of experience in fintech and fast-paced educational startup and continuously striving to expand skill sets. Proficient in Python/Django and Golang. Aspiring to be part of a team that solves problems using technology and learn new things. Have a bachelor's degree in Computer Science.

Technical Skills

Operating Systems GNU/Linux (Ubuntu, Arch Linux), Windows

Programming Python, Golang, JavaScript

Web HTML, CSS

Tools Kafka

Docker DevOps AWS, EC2, S3
Frameworks Django, VueJs
Version Control System Git, GitLab, GitHub

Experience

Zerodha Hamilton, New Zealand

Nov. 2020 - Oct. 2020

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (REMOTE)

Moved to Hamilton and working remotely for Zerodha.

• Built crm for our support agents using frappe framework/Python

Zerodha Bengaluru, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER May, 2017 - Oct., 2020

Zerodha is India's largest stock broker with more than 4 million clients. Part of 30 member tech team.

- Develop and maintain system for all payins for our trading system
- Rewrote our payment system from Python to Golang
- Integrated with several bank APIs
- Desinged and Integrated UPI flow in our system
- Wrote python clients for interal communication system
- Designed and implemented REST APIs for support calls integration
- Wrote a Golang utility program to sync all data from Kafka to DB

Entri.me Kerala, India

PRODUCT ENGINEER Feb. 2015 - Apr. 2017

Entri, is education based product startup that provides a Plug and Play learning system for teachers and students in India. 23,000 students, 400 teachers, and 32 institutes have used Entri to improve their learning and teaching so far. Entri is the first company from India to get selected into LearnLaunch in Boston, USA.

- · One of the initial employees
- · Designed a payment processing system and integrated with Payumoney and Razorpay for processing the payments
- Integrated with SendGrid for transactional emails and Mvaayoo for transactional SMS
- Designed and implemented REST APIs to support entri.me Android Application
- Developed responsive web applications with Bootstrap and Sass preprocessor
- Created dashboard to track and analyse student performance for teachers

Recursive Labs Kerala, India

SOFTWARE TRAINEE March. 2014 - Jan. 2015

Mentorship program to become a better programmer by reading books, writing code, participating in Massive Open Online Courses(MOOC) and pursuing personal projects.

- Used GNU/Linux Operating System from day 1 and did Python based projects and programming assignments.
- Gained exposure in developing web applications using Python based frameworks like Django and Flask

March 4, 2021 Jibin Jose · Résumé 1

Projects

Mvaayoo Python

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JOSEJIBIN/MVAAYOO-PYTHON

• Python wrapper around Mvaayoo API

URL Shortener (Archived)

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JOSEJIBIN/URL-SHORTENER

- A simple URL shortener application
- Written using the Django framework
- Ability to create custom short URLs

Volunteer Experience

Django Girls Workshop

Соасн

Django Girls is a community that empowers and helps women to organize free, one-day programming workshop for 30-60 people about building their first application using HTML, CSS, Python and Django.

• coached Django Girls Thiruvananthapuram event organized by students from LBSITW

Education

Kerala University

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

• Organised inter college computer science fest

Mar. 2009 - 2013